
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <channel>
   <title>games on monkyyy.science</title>
   <link>https://monkyyy.science/categories/games/</link>
   <description>Recent content in games on monkyyy.science</description>
   <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
   <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
   
       <atom:link href="https://monkyyy.science/categories/games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
   
     <item>
       <title>variable length data words</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/variable_length_data_words/</link>
       <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/variable_length_data_words/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a trade-off between efficient pointer sizes and the fundamental max data allowed by your system. You can not have more memory than pointer size X the word size, period. If you want systems with more the 8 GB of ram or whatever tiny amount of hard drive space you needed to upgrade to 64 bit, which affected the fundamental choice of your pointers. What was the consequence of that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it depends how you use the pointers, but let&amp;rsquo;s meme for a bit and assume you had a doubly-linked list of bools. That is to say, you used 2 pointers and a bool to store each bool to get the magic properties of linked lists; sooooo 64*2+1 rounded up to 8, 136 bits, to store 1 bit of data. Given that moving data to the processor is the slowest operation on the computer, this is terrible, very very terrible. Yet that&amp;rsquo;s kinda the world we live in how inefficiently we use computers but I digress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we want to live in a world with giant ram and hard drives. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re following the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kZRE7HIO3vk&#34;&gt;call to write a new isa&lt;/a&gt;, or making a virtual machine I would find comfy; I would suggest looking at the other side of that pointer x word size equation that&amp;rsquo;s flexible; the word sizes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We live in a post simd world, data can come in giant chunks, the 8 size word&amp;hellip; isn&amp;rsquo;t used really, like an 8-bit int is frankly rare to see, its awkward for bools, it may not run well, and when your working with a simd of 64-bit ints its a level of precision, not necessary. Could we go to 32-bit pointers and 32-bit word sizes, dropping support for 8/16 bit ints? Sure but that makes bools even more silly(and compressing bools into 32 bits would be insane bitshifting).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leading me to my suggestion, variable-length data words; what if depending on where in the data you were a bump of the pointer moved you a different amount of data forward? A pointer at the 7th memory address was a different amount of bits away from the 8th than the 2^16th and 2^16+1th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would suggest 3 sizes of data, bools, 32/64 bits, and then a giant simd type let&amp;rsquo;s say 8*64. Naturally compressed bools(and bitshifting), a reasonable data size for standard computation, and then massive data for massive storage sizes and simd. That should cover all the bases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s suppose you have a 16-bit pointer, a prefix of 00 means it&amp;rsquo;s in the bools memory, 01 means the 64-bit memory, 11 means the 8*64 simd; leaving you 14-bit pointers for each, how much data is that? Well, 2^14+2^14*64+2^14(8*64)= 9453568, or 1.18 megabytes; compared to what the simple 16-bit pointer with 8-bit words gets you of 2^16*8=524288, 65.5 kilobytes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe this complexity gets you quite a bit, lets return to that doubly linked list of bools, 16*2+1, or 33, still terrible but less so. Maybe there be a reason to use some of these data structures with pointers if they were cheap enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;d probably want to make the pointer size 32 bit and have some metadata somewhere or something, or maybe even imbalance it a little; it&amp;rsquo;s kinda unclear to me how to design a fresh isa since there hasn&amp;rsquo;t been one in a while but throwing this idea out there. But I&amp;rsquo;m convinced there&amp;rsquo;s a good answer to the question of how to design a isa with variable length data words.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>community building</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/community_building/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/community_building/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Heres an email update link that may work: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mailchi.mp/1b14f5937da7/emails&#34;&gt;https://mailchi.mp/1b14f5937da7/emails&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and heres my tiny discord (where there is zero rules): &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/PfX6R9CrFZ&#34;&gt;https://discord.gg/PfX6R9CrFZ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have zero tracking, and have no idea if anyone is reading save for one person who has emailed me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:monkyyy@cocaine.ninja&#34;&gt;monkyyy@cocaine.ninja&lt;/a&gt; to say my rss feed didn&amp;rsquo;t work for such a such program (which I dont know how to do anything about).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like email updates &lt;em&gt;shrug&lt;/em&gt;, I know I should use rss in thoery but like most things are spooky email and so&amp;hellip;. I have one to.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>review of D</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/review_of_d/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/review_of_d/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip; D, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it for a while and I have some opinions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it stands I would not suggest picking up D for metaprogramming or as your language for the next 2 decades but for your next small project with modest goals it&amp;rsquo;s a maybe. This space of C replacements has several newcomers in it, D will likely be my 3rd pick at the end of the day, I don&amp;rsquo;t know who wins, but it won&amp;rsquo;t be the old horse, it will be one of the risky new experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D as a C replacement is stable, launched, and has bindings to the c ecosystem today; BUT, its meta programming is flawed and inadequate for building new better paradigms, the compiler is buggy and that won&amp;rsquo;t be changing in the foreseeable future and it fell for many of last generations memes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pros:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No Cdecl needed, it has complexities(mostly 2d arrays are defined backward) but you will not need to learn the spiral method. Types are defined reading left to right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simplified templates. I own the red book, I can&amp;rsquo;t read it for shit, I learned templates in D and while they are still insane and wonky, simple patterns are possible and several quality of life things were added over c++. I take that on faith since I don&amp;rsquo;t and won&amp;rsquo;t be learning c++ templates, but the example code I&amp;rsquo;ve seen is quite convincing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s stable today; this can&amp;rsquo;t be overstated, most of the c replacement langs are young, and my favorite in the race, Jai hasn&amp;rsquo;t shipped a compiler yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mixins and ctfe; you can inject strings into code at compile-time and set compile-time constants with standard runtime code. Real attempts to make decent metaprogramming that&amp;rsquo;s quite a bit more sane than the python/c++ meme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a c++ replacement not truly a c replacement. With ranges(iterators) and templates and having oo memes; the aim was off the mark, it&amp;rsquo;s a related goal of course, but it&amp;rsquo;s very clear there are philosophical differences here. The GC, while I don&amp;rsquo;t actually care I can use big arrays of plain old structs anyway but as a feature suggests the philosophical difference that is labor not spent on fundamentals I would care about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Safetyphila; there are several indefensible design choices with their explanation being preemptive safety. Why are int promoted rules fucked, safety; why is there complexity to treat a file as a string compile-time, safety; why doesn&amp;rsquo;t Compile-Time Function Execution have access to the full feature set, safety; why were they thinking of mimicking rust and by default marking all code as safe(meaning lots of code I write will need to be marked unsafe verbosely), safety. Why is a lot of the std so very verbose with a few examples I know about being wildly complex and slowing down compile times when a simple 5 line block of code would do the same job, safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poor namespace management; &amp;ldquo;__traits&amp;rdquo;, like oh my god what is that shit, why are there namespace conflicts of common functions when you &amp;ldquo;import std&amp;rdquo;. The std is organized &amp;hellip; poorly, to say the least, the functions for &amp;ldquo;I want to do functional programming now&amp;rdquo; in the suggested style are split up at least 4 places (if not 5)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bug list is long, with no end in sight. I do not have the slightest hope the bugs I run into will be fixed and there are many, there are 2 extremely common bugs for delegates that kneecap any hope in using them in abusive ways. Templates and context are strange and often not worth looking into if you run into bugs; instead, you should drop the approach and attempt a different more procedural solution to the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One arm is tied behind your back with all types of metaprogramming; whether it&amp;rsquo;s safetyphila or the bugs; all the meta-programming patterns and paradigms I&amp;rsquo;ve looked into, have nuance that makes it not something to trust. I want my tools very sharp; templates, opoverload duck typing, &amp;ldquo;alias this&amp;rdquo; abuse, ctfe + mixins, even the suggested functional programming with std; etc. all are scratched and dented with irritating land mines ready to trip you up if you want to learn the hard way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s enough of a rant, hopefully, one of the new c replacements are paying attention and manage to dodge these issues, for the time being, this is a soft suggestion its probably possible to start on whatever project today in d; but avoid the Koolaid, be wildly skeptical of any claims that it all just works and plan on headaches.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>cruiseship seasteading</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/cruiseship_seasteading/</link>
       <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/cruiseship_seasteading/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;The sea, not space is the next frontier, it&amp;rsquo;s quite a bit closer and economical to send settlers there. 2/3rds of the earth surface is actually unclaimed by nation-states and while there are challenges for making it work, likely internet access with being expensive and slow, it not speculative high concept engineering to live there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To my knowledge, there are two ongoing attempts and I have complaints about both, and would quickly like to suggest a 3rd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To quickly summarize the other two, Chad Elwartowski and the seasteading institute:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chad, some bitcoin investor ordered to have a seasteading house built, this tiny shack, and then hired out so boats to drag it out off the coast of Thailand. He is was/being tried for treason by Thailand with the death plenty being talked about and decided to not deal with it and abandoned the small shack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the drastic, another side of the spectrum is the seasteading institute. Which produces many artist renditions of what seastead could look like and it&amp;rsquo;s all super sci-fi and is in talks with some small nation to get some legal permission to do it. I.e. minarchists cucks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If my opinion is clear from how I described them, I think chad is based but stupid, and I think the seasteading institute will be endlessly tied up in talks forever and I&amp;rsquo;m not all interested in asking permission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the thing, there are already floating cities that flout laws; cruise ships. They aren&amp;rsquo;t self-sustainable and I honestly think they are shitty entitlement capitalism to the core but&amp;hellip;. well they exist and aren&amp;rsquo;t being tried for treason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So as a core idea, you, yes you, ancap billionaire with your bitcoin. You go buy a used small cruise ship and park it off the American coast or a related western country with a strong culture for individualism and start selling sections of the ship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some throwing shit at the wall industries to look into:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quiet bed and breakfast. Cuirseships survive off tourism, mixing low labor costs with middle-class money. You could do much the same, but I would pull back on the entitlement, the 24/7 buffet, and shows, etc. just a room near water and likely an interesting culture is a vacation enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saltwater experimental crops. There are experimentalists in this space looking at this idea, in theory, you could make some deal with a researching university one wanting to make crops in seawater and use these crops to supplement the local diet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drug manufacturing, I would travel to have one of the experimental LSD + therapist treatments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gambling. Las Vegas exists, and that dessert isn&amp;rsquo;t pleasant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would note you likely could invite some of the illegal immigrants for low-cost labor like with the cruise industry in general&amp;hellip; but treat them better, rent them out small spaces for restaurants and other self-employment rather than running them ragged with 16 hour days with the centrally planning that is a cruise ship.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>shower algorithm</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/shower_algrothiums/</link>
       <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/shower_algrothiums/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;So a few days ago an algorithm for k-largest came to me in the shower and I&amp;rsquo;ve been having migraines thinking about the problem since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It started as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;take a sample of the array&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;deduce the shape of the array&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;compile a pivot function&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;based on that pivot function, move elements to the front of the array getting a smaller array&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;repeat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was literally considering writing jit asm to make that pivot function for a while during migraines. I highly don&amp;rsquo;t recommend this sort of process, very not fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;anyway I eventually settled on a different algorithm that is correct and sane&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;do a radix count&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;process the radix count array to get a pivot number of which digit contains k&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;run thru the array with radix function and filter elements that equal the pivot number to the front of the array and numbers under the pivot number to an output array&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;repeat on the smaller slice with the next radix function&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are more details to make it work and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/crazymonkyyy/radix/blob/master/radixksmallest.d&#34;&gt;it does work&lt;/a&gt;; but&amp;hellip;. it isn&amp;rsquo;t faster than the existing algorithm its ties with the pivot-based algorithm in d&amp;rsquo;s std. (I&amp;rsquo;m literally crying rn, sadpepe.jpg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reasoning why it seems to tie would be that while my code should decrease the problem by 1/256(for the unaware the standard size for radix digits once optimized, so for 64-bit numbers, you have 4 iterations) it does touch the data twice, while the pivot based algorithm decreases the code in half each iteration and to be sloppy math 1 + 1/2 + 1/4&amp;hellip; does equal 2; so yes roughly the same, if you assume that the problem is decreased by 1/256, is trivial and ignorable; which&amp;hellip;. yeah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(again literally crying; hold me&amp;hellip; why wasn&amp;rsquo;t I just magically smarter than everyone else with a few days of thinking with migraines)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, I have a differently working code for the problem, and I&amp;rsquo;m imagining ways that maybe are loose on correctness but do work on the insight that a radix digit+number is a good discriminator function&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens if do a random sample of the array with radix digits and process the count array of this sample with a heuristic of some kind? Assuming I&amp;rsquo;m ok with being loose on correctness, I could touch the majority of data once, but the complexities of recursive algorithms with template messes made writing the last version hard so I want some outside advice and thoughts on the matter if only to clarify my thoughts into something sane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are some known ways to manage multi streams of data as you filtering? If you&amp;rsquo;re discarding down data it&amp;rsquo;s possible to have nice space complicity, with radix you can sort nicely; but inbetween seems kinda a mess, the radix sort depends on perfect knowledge of counts as far as I&amp;rsquo;m aware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway enough rambling, if anyone has any thoughts wherever my email at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:monkyyy@cocaine.ninja&#34;&gt;monkyyy@cocaine.ninja&lt;/a&gt; if you don&amp;rsquo;t know me someway else.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>sunzones</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/sunzones/</link>
       <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/sunzones/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;So, time zones and daylight savings, what&amp;rsquo;s the deal with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, there are 3 fundamental details to the discussion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long-distance coordinated time is valuable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans are willing to care about this standard over their own health, i.e. people don&amp;rsquo;t change their alarms the day before daylight savings and tell their bosses &amp;ldquo;nah&amp;rdquo; west side of time zones have higher rates of sleep-related issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sun moves across the surface of the earth in a distinctly unhelpful organic way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So not only fuck daylight savings(but why are you asking permission to not arbitrary change your sleep schedule from your robits and politicians, anyway?) fuck timezones in the case of America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suggest a radical shift, America should have a single time zone, and 12 sun zones. This time zone should not have daylight savings even, it should just be the declared American time zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In its place, there should an artificial declared time the sun raises separated by 15-minute chunks and cut up however convenient. That&amp;rsquo;s a touch absurd given that it changes by time of year and if there are mountains nearby, but all the same, there should be a systematic declared sunrise time for the replacement. Because people apparently will change their behavior and it affects their health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you implement the following policies, be grumpy with corporations that open let&amp;rsquo;s say before an hour after the sunrise. Phone default settings for do-not-disturb are set to by -9 hours before this sun raise and +1 after. Make these national-sized systems start listing their operating times as &amp;ldquo;sun+X hours&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No more having to need more time zone information from Americans. I as a hyper-capitalist do adore the industrialized train networks, but they weren&amp;rsquo;t trying to design a system for people to sleep properly or anything of the sort, this is a relic of redesigning of the last norms around time, it can be redesigned again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>ubi predictions</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/ubi_predictions/</link>
       <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/ubi_predictions/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;So as we get the 2nd and there is talk of a 3rd stimulus check, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about what it was, a test run for Ubi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I imagine public support for Ubi has never been higher, I don&amp;rsquo;t understand the politics which drive welfare design making in the slightest, but I imagine the chance it happens soon to be raising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s assume Ubi starts in 2023 and its now the year is 2028. What do I expect to happen during this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moderate deurbanization. American cities are cesspits and wildly unhealthy, there is some slow trickle of people fleeing them as is, Ubi would be a carrot to this stick. I believe people stay in the cities because they imagine it&amp;rsquo;s where the work is. If there is a flat payment it should occur to many that moving somewhere with a lower cost of living is an option. I don&amp;rsquo;t understand why people stay in cities currently so many would probably stay for these mystery reasons hence &amp;ldquo;moderate&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radical raise in odd jobs and wildly unrealistic self-employment; an &amp;ldquo;unsticking&amp;rdquo; of the 40 hour workweek. Financial freedom and security, isn&amp;rsquo;t something people traditionally have, it would be radically new. While there is talk that &amp;ldquo;no one would work&amp;rdquo; Nah, people are still incapable of budgeting and the payment would likely be just below the standard of living by design; it would however give flexibility in how, and many would forego security and status of a standard job for a different style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expansion of illegal immigration even further, calls to restrict legal immigrants on account of the&amp;hellip; neo-middle classes(?) sake, while they engage in hiring out in using illegal immigrant labor. House cleaners, fast food workers, and other luxury service work will likely drop away from the young and uneducated masses of Americans while demand increase as the people still working normal jobs would demand such small luxuries. It&amp;rsquo;s not hard to imagine in between the chaos illegal immigrants fill the gaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dominance of the dollar is questioned, but not broken. America will still be the cultural and military superpower, but people will raise their eyebrows. There will likely need to be moves to protect the dollar, absurdly high taxes on wealth or land and the laundering money scheme of the American war machine would be slowed, something, politicians would be extremely dumb to not mitigate harm somehow. But if currency wasn&amp;rsquo;t cultural, bitcoin would have already won, and if anything the Ubi would be an insane show of dominance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The edge case art markets become common knowledge, decrease in price but radically expand in volume. Rare pepes, furries designs; if you&amp;rsquo;re unaware there are fringe art markets, that confuse even me; but they exist and are likely driven by causal income and unlike anything else are not finite. Let&amp;rsquo;s not go crazy and assume that the 1000$ furries pictures become the norm, let&amp;rsquo;s say 20$ here or there for some custom art, impulse buys once a month but people with weak self-control for a half-baked self-employment culture for artists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>complex games &lt;3</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/complex_games_3/</link>
       <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/complex_games_3/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;So, valve has stopped dev on artifact for the 2nd time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sadness, pure sadness, I put so much money in. Money, I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked both versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, so last year I loved 3 complex games, artifact, artifact 2 electric boogaloo, and 5d chess.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/chessplaytime.png&#34; alt=&#34;chessplaytime&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/artifactplaytime.png&#34; alt=&#34;artfactplaytime&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/artfact2playtime.png&#34; alt=&#34;artfact2playtime&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story with each is the same I feel, an insanely steep learning curve with a first-order strategy that hurts the new players, into a decline in play base and this handful of theory crafters solving the high end of the game without the devs reacting to balance problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With artifact 1, it was red having the strongest heroes by a large margin and a very strong 1 card win condiction in a game where heroes weren&amp;rsquo;t random in a game with a lot of randomnesses. Red needed to be nerfed hard and quickly, the market valued ax at some absurd price because he was in both easy-to-play strong decks mono-red and ramp green red.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With artifact 2, I&amp;rsquo;m less sure I didn&amp;rsquo;t get an invite till late last year, but there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of agro black that&amp;rsquo;s quite tricky to survive&amp;hellip;. it was less extreme mostly any theoretical player base hated valve. So no player base was picked up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With 5d chess there&amp;rsquo;s a 3 move opening that exposes the king&amp;hellip; when the king is very weak and the dev was too slow to add &amp;ldquo;princess&amp;rdquo; a variant where the queen is weakened to be rook + bishop and not the trigonally, quadgonally moving, &amp;ldquo;random&amp;rdquo; checkmate machine. That the queen was extremely strong should have been seen very early and I have trouble imagining that wasn&amp;rsquo;t something considered even prerelease. But it was quite late and not a first-week patch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kinda want to make my own &amp;ldquo;5d&amp;rdquo; game, but I have zero belief in my ability to balance such a thing when I clearly can&amp;rsquo;t understand other peoples perspective why they dropped these games, soooo, heres my advice for any such games in the future:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can not be perfect information deterministic like 5d chess; with such a large attack surface and presumably the type of player who will find a clever degenerate stat. the criticism of artifact 1 about being too random doesn&amp;rsquo;t really apply, the heroes as big numbers i.e. the red heroes weren&amp;rsquo;t that random, any red hero would kill any blue hero so only really very high-level play saw blue existence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need a causal mode that removes details for new players to play new players, the hero draft of artifact 2 seems to be helpful here and maybe with it being free, there will be a player base for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need drastic balance levers you pull quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Randomness needs all the dev talk on input vs output, and information horizons likely need to be skillfully done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/chess_showingoff.png&#34; alt=&#34;chess_showingoff&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/artfact_showoff.png&#34; alt=&#34;artfact_showoff&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/artfact2_showoff.png&#34; alt=&#34;artfact_showoff&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(So everyone take some nootropics/cocaine and stop leaving these types of games without playerbases)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>monkyyy markup</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/monkyyy_markup/</link>
       <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/monkyyy_markup/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Soooo, gopher and related projects are too limited, html5 has 3d rendering which is insane, and markup by carelessly using all the symbols breaks the ability to write out Japanese emotes, or even how you write out math. And there are new desires like twitch emotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(ﾉ&amp;gt;ω&amp;lt;)ﾉ :｡･:* :･ﾟ&#39;★,｡･: *:･ﾟ&#39;☆&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here&amp;rsquo;s a theoretical spec for what markup lang I&amp;rsquo;d make, with the following goals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;light on &amp;ldquo;symbol namespace&amp;rdquo; pollution&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;having color (looking at you markdown)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;easy to write free flow without looking anything up&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a (sane) level of expandability&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[b] - bolds text&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[i] - itatics text&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[c] - crosses out text&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[h1] - header&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[t1] - opinionated indent level, for code formating that survives whitespace sanitizing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&amp;gt;] - quote&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[^] - small expont-like text&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[*] - bulletpoint&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[pepe] draws a twitch emote style Pepe(decided by a community that thinks Pepe is more important than the family emoji having 6 racial versions by 3*3*3 gendered versions, your fucking morons unicode, open-source emotes in sprite sheets up on github somewhere). For sanity require it to be at least 4 letters and symbol-less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[duckduckgo.com] - link&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[monkyyy.science/pepe.jpg] - &amp;ldquo;resource&amp;rdquo;, inlined if supported by the client, downloads to temp and opened by xdg-open when clicked otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[] - resets text drawing to baseline, i.e. &amp;ldquo;[b]bold[] not bold&amp;rdquo;, not the nested shit of html&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[00F] - simple rgb hexadecimal, color &lt;em&gt;hints&lt;/em&gt; if its the first element in the block of text sets the background color otherwise text color, if the user has a dark theme blue would make a dark blue background, if the user had bright theme a sky blue. Details would be left up to the client but the basic assumption would be no color combo should be unreadable. Maybe allow G-Z to overflow like &amp;ldquo;200% blue&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/n - endline should also reset the styling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;maybe [[] and []] for &amp;ldquo;escaped&amp;rdquo; brackets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, 1 and 2 letter codes would be for text style details, 3 letter codes would be colors, 4 and more its either an emote or a link.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>polycenteric law</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/polycenteric_law/</link>
       <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/polycenteric_law/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;feature&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; of polycentric law, I would define as: &amp;ldquo;having multiple legal authorities active in the same geographical area&amp;rdquo;. This naturally is in light conflict with the definition of nation-states used in ancap: &amp;ldquo;A monopoly on &lt;em&gt;violent&lt;/em&gt; legal authority over a geographical area&amp;rdquo;. Not mutually exclusive, but I would suggest the more total the state the less polycentric it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polycentric law is everywhere&lt;/strong&gt;, in every functional system I&amp;rsquo;m aware of, the most glaring example of which is in America corporations shop for a tax rate between the states, but with little restrictions on this getting in the way of their economic activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Kowloon walled city there were 5 crime families, and well Kowloon was growing in population &lt;em&gt;while Mao&amp;rsquo;s china starved&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s unclear how that was functioning but it was likely mafia-style feud law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Somalia they have &amp;ldquo;blood feuds&amp;rdquo;, where your family tree determines your court, your 3rd cousin if deemed the best person in your clan is your judge for family disputes or something like that, getting a complex network based on family relations. And they were &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.peterleeson.com/Better_Off_Stateless.pdf&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;better off stateless&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then religion, oh my god religion, the original legal systems pre-separation of church and state. If you&amp;rsquo;re wondering why Europe hates jews as money-grabbing, they were allowing &amp;ldquo;usury&amp;rdquo; when the catholic church wasn&amp;rsquo;t. and christen bankers were angry about it. When I as a capitalist would say the usury was likely necessary to make modern capitalism. Furthermore, the separation is kinda weak, like I&amp;rsquo;m in Utah, there was a church building on my highschool campus with a synced schedule with the school so I could have religious education implied to be on par with anything else taught.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In nation-states this is a hierarchy of courts usually, do understand this is very much a part of your life now, a complex web of courts you don&amp;rsquo;t understand following &lt;em&gt;different rules, different norms, that only works at all because you rarely need to use it&lt;/em&gt;. Furthermore, there are likely elements of capitalism affecting you, most modern contracts will have arbitration clauses, these are private systems that have added themselves to the bottom of the current hierarchy. Keep that in mind as I describe what I want here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I as an ancap, want to extend polycentric law, in an ideal world instead of family, religion, or the hierarchy geography, I would want political party &lt;strong&gt;you pick&lt;/strong&gt; and pay for to decide the law in you live under. Start-up cities are a similar idea but are still in the geographical mindset to avoid conflict with current nation-states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why? Well, existing polycentric law elements are random and poorly planned. Bloodlines, invisible sky men, and mafias are no way to organize society(even if they are better than states). While the nation-states&amp;rsquo; polycentrism is fragile, in America the federal government is always growing. I&amp;rsquo;m sure the UK had a growing list of reasons to dislike the EU. etc. &lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not great if an important element of the legal system&lt;/strong&gt; you believe makes it functional &lt;strong&gt;is eroding, always, causally&lt;/strong&gt;. Also &lt;em&gt;moving between states to pick between red and blue isn&amp;rsquo;t the level of freedom I&amp;rsquo;m looking for.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make a careless argument in its favor, I would suggest two aspects: robustness, and experimentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For robustness, consider that California is fucking insane, while being likely the strongest state, failing in several measures, if their insanity was affecting elsewhere would America still be standing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For experimentation, there was a first state the legalized gay marriage, weed, LSD, and who knows what else on into the future, and despite calls by the evangelists saying these things would cause god to smite America I have yet to hear of a politician struck by lighting the day/hour/minute such laws are passed. And you can just look up their crime rates and other sorts of stats after the fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The freedom afforded to corporations to shop for tax rates needs to be expanded to all.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Consider reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.daviddfriedman.com/Academic/Course_Pages/legal_systems_very_different_12/LegalSystemsDraft.html&#34;&gt;David Friedman&lt;/a&gt; if interested.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>devlog</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/devlog/</link>
       <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/devlog/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip; I started a rewrite to organize things in my game a while ago; longer than I&amp;rsquo;m going to admit to. But it&amp;rsquo;s done now, it&amp;rsquo;s working on a fundamental level, with a level of organization under it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or to put it another way, it took months between these two screenshots:
&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/newscreenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;newscreenshot.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/oldscreenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;oldscreenshot.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programing is alienating in the Marxist sense, extremely so, and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how to deal with that. This progress doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel real. Here the different file structures, so a lot did happen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;before&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;├── art.png
├── bar.d
├── carts.png
├── dub.json
├── dub.selections.json
├── foo.d
├── hello
├── mix
├── PixAntiqua.ttf
├── random code
│   └── shaderattempt.d
├── raylib_cheatsheet.pdf
├── raylib-d.wiki
│   ├── Docs-&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;cheatsheet&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;.md
│   └── Home.md
├── source
│   ├── app.d
│   ├── connectedcomponent.d
│   ├── draw.mix
│   ├── gameplay.mix
│   ├── group.mix
│   ├── libraylib.a
│   ├── libraylib.so
│   ├── __main-b9b3f17.o
│   ├── orecombo-60ce4ba.o
│   ├── orecombo.d
│   ├── orecombo.o
│   ├── orelist.d
│   ├── oremangiment.d
│   ├── rangematch.d
│   ├── raylib.dll
│   ├── raylib.lib
│   ├── ringarray.d
│   ├── smart2darray.d
│   ├── stable.mix
│   └── table.d
└── wave.fs
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;after&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;├── art
│   ├── art1x
│   │   ├── art.png
│   │   ├── buttons.png
│   │   ├── carts2.png
│   │   ├── carts.jpeg
│   │   └── carts.png
│   ├── art2x
│   │   ├── art.png
│   │   └── buttons.png
│   ├── art5x
│   │   └── art.png
│   ├── arts sources
│   │   ├── Donate.url
│   │   ├── Facebook.url
│   │   ├── License.txt
│   │   ├── PNG
│   │   │   ├── Blue
│   │   │   │   ├── letter_A.png

│   │   │   ├── Brown
│   │   │   │   ├── letter_A.png

│   │   │   ├── Marble
│   │   │   │   ├── letter_A.png

│   │   │   ├── Metal
│   │   │   │   ├── letter_A.png

│   │   │   ├── Solid
│   │   │   │   ├── letter_A.png

│   │   │   ├── Wood
│   │   │   │   ├── letter_A.png

│   │   │   └── Yellow
│   │   │       ├── letter_A.png

│   │   ├── Preview.png
│   │   ├── Sample.png
│   │   ├── Spritesheet
│   │   │   ├── blue_spritesheet.png
│   │   │   ├── blue_spritesheet.xml
│   │   │   ├── box_spritesheet.png
│   │   │   ├── box_spritesheet.xml
│   │   │   ├── brown_spritesheet.png
│   │   │   ├── brown_spritesheet.xml
│   │   │   ├── marble_spritesheet.png
│   │   │   ├── marble_spritesheet.xml
│   │   │   ├── metal_spritesheet.png
│   │   │   ├── metal_spritesheet.xml
│   │   │   ├── solid_spritesheet.png
│   │   │   ├── solid_spritesheet.xml
│   │   │   ├── wood_spritesheet.png
│   │   │   ├── wood_spritesheet.xml
│   │   │   ├── yellow_spritesheet.png
│   │   │   └── yellow_spritesheet.xml
│   │   └── Vector
│   │       ├── lettertiles_vector.ai
│   │       ├── lettertiles_vector.svg
│   │       └── lettertiles_vector.swf
│   ├── dub.json
│   ├── dub.selections.json
│   ├── mix
│   ├── PixAntiqua.ttf
│   ├── raylib
│   └── source
│       ├── app.d
│       ├── artscale.mix
│       ├── imageloader.mix
│       └── initwindow.mix
├── board
│   ├── dub.json
│   ├── dub.selections.json
│   ├── mix
│   ├── raylib
│   └── source
│       ├── app.d
│       ├── board.mix
│       ├── fakedraw.mix
│       ├── fakeorecombo.d
│       ├── initwindow.mix
│       ├── oreque.mix
│       └── ringarray.d
├── collision
│   ├── dub.json
│   ├── dub.selections.json
│   ├── mix
│   ├── raylib
│   └── source
│       ├── app.d
│       └── mayomath.d
├── encyclopedia
│   ├── dub.json
│   ├── dub.selections.json
│   ├── ency
│   │   ├── foo
│   │   └── table
│   ├── mix
│   ├── raylib
│   └── source
│       ├── app.d
│       ├── app.old
│       ├── cashe.d
│       ├── eccentricexpressions.d
│       ├── encyclopedia.mix
│       ├── page_.d
│       ├── parse.d
│       └── ui.d
├── journal
│   ├── dub.json
│   ├── dub.selections.json
│   ├── mix
│   ├── raylib
│   └── source
│       ├── app.d
│       ├── journal.d
│       └── ui.d
├── launcher
│   ├── dub.json
│   ├── dub.selections.json
│   ├── mix
│   ├── out
│   ├── out2
│   ├── raylib
│   └── source
│       └── app.d
├── link
├── link2
├── link3
├── link4
├── linkart
├── link.d
├── main
│   ├── art1x
│   │   ├── art.png
│   │   ├── buttons.png
│   │   └── carts2.png
│   ├── art2x
│   │   ├── art.png
│   │   └── buttons.png
│   ├── art5x
│   │   └── art.png
│   ├── dub.json
│   ├── dub.selections.json
│   ├── mix
│   ├── raylib
│   ├── source
│   │   ├── app.d
│   │   ├── artscale.mix
│   │   ├── board.mix
│   │   ├── cashe.d
│   │   ├── ctfestrings.d
│   │   ├── eccentricexpressions.d
│   │   ├── encyclopedia.mix
│   │   ├── imageloader.mix
│   │   ├── initwindow.mix
│   │   ├── journal.d
│   │   ├── mayomath.d
│   │   ├── orecombo.d
│   │   ├── ore_.d
│   │   ├── oreque.mix
│   │   ├── oretable.d
│   │   ├── page_.d
│   │   ├── parse.d
│   │   ├── playfulbuttons.mix
│   │   ├── rangematch.d
│   │   ├── ringarray.d
│   │   ├── scenecontrol.mix
│   │   ├── todolist.d
│   │   ├── uglyconnectedcomponent.d
│   │   └── ui.d
│   └── todo
├── ore
│   ├── ctfestrings.d
│   ├── dub.json
│   ├── orecombo.d
│   ├── orecombo.d.old
│   ├── ore_.d
│   ├── oreque.d.old
│   ├── oretable.d
│   ├── out
│   ├── rangematch.d
│   └── uglyconnectedcomponent.d
├── particals
│   └── dub.json
├── README.md
├── scenes
│   ├── dub.json
│   ├── dub.selections.json
│   ├── mix
│   ├── raylib
│   └── source
│       ├── app.d
│       ├── fakebuttonsprites.mix
│       ├── fakescenedepends.mix
│       ├── mayomath.d
│       ├── playfulbuttons.mix
│       ├── scenecontrol.mix
│       └── ui.d
├── systemlist
├── template
│   ├── dub.json
│   ├── dub.selections.json
│   ├── mix
│   └── source
│       └── app.d
├── todo
│   ├── dub.json
│   ├── dub.selections.json
│   ├── mix
│   ├── raylib
│   ├── source
│   │   ├── app.d
│   │   ├── cashe.d
│   │   ├── eccentricexpressions.d
│   │   ├── example
│   │   ├── example.d.dubisstupid
│   │   ├── example.o
│   │   ├── out
│   │   ├── parse.d
│   │   ├── todo
│   │   └── todolist.d
│   └── todo
├── toyui
│   ├── dub.json
│   ├── dub.selections.json
│   ├── mix
│   ├── particals
│   └── source
│       ├── app.d
│       └── ui.d
├── tree
├── ulty
└── utilityfiles
	├── cashe.d
	├── ctfestrings.d
	├── dub.json
	├── eccentricexpressions
	├── eccentricexpressions.d
	├── eccentricexpressions.o
	├── fuzz.d
	├── golbal_state.d
	├── math.d
	├── mayomath.d
	├── mix
	├── mutatetemplate.d
	├── parse.d
	├── rangematch.d
	├── ringarray.d
	├── superstate.d
	└── uglyconnectedcomponent.d
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;note there are a lot of hard links here, and I want a source control thing that manages hard links(git doesn&amp;rsquo;t and everything looks hacky), if anyone has any insight&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>irresponsibly is responsibly</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/irresponsibly_is_rsponsibly/</link>
       <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/irresponsibly_is_rsponsibly/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;By which I do mean legal irresponsibility and personal responsibility. To quickly define the former since it&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily used and I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely sure I use it correctly, I mean control over a resource without a possibility of legal consequences. I.e. most understandings of property are understood to be irresponsible but managing a trust fund is a legal responsibility, if you screw it up you&amp;rsquo;re getting sued, if you&amp;rsquo;re renting and paint the walls a color the landlord hates, you&amp;rsquo;re getting sued. If you live in a nationstate and despite your pure belief in self-ownership try to sell a kidney, you go to prison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This irresponsibility is critical to my understanding of ownership. If there are high property taxes and the state will plan to take your assets if you fail to pay, I don&amp;rsquo;t see that as being secure ownership, the state is claiming to be a landlord with extra steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe there should be a singular irresponsible owner of a resource in most cases. If you have multiple, you get the tragedy of the commons, which the suggested solution is usually to make the state an owner, my solution would be to usually consider the previous use homesteading and to spilt the grassland up somehow. If they are a responsible owner with unclear incentives, well they are a renter and renting promotes irresponsibility as you don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily feel the consequences, it becomes an externality to chase you down in court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to be too hard on all legal responsibility, but it&amp;rsquo;s a risk to have someone who is not you affect your resources. A bad trust fund manager can steal from you, a bad renter can destroy the flooring. But at the same time, it&amp;rsquo;s awkward to be these people, a trust fund manager is likely pushed to be too risk-averse, a renter is like &amp;ldquo;do have to ask before throwing away the pile of trash in the utility closet&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s a source of friction even with good actors, which the world isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily full of good actors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We as a society should be strongly for small scale absolute ownership of resources, and for the most part, we are, &amp;ldquo;ownership is 9/10th of the law&amp;rdquo; according to common law, and well common law was at America and Britain at the time of the industrial revolution. Not to mention the difference between Maoist China and Hongkong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When your answer to no one you can be creative, uproot systems. If you have a smoker who&amp;rsquo;s trying to quit, common advice would be to destroy any cigarettes they have and try to never buy any more, if they signed a 5-year contract to get a box delivered to their house weekly and they have to keep paying. Well, that&amp;rsquo;s a responsibility and that freedom isn&amp;rsquo;t there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of bitcoin and smart contracts was that ownership of a piece of knowledge is 10/10ths of the law, self-ownership is mostly about defending other&amp;rsquo;s irresponsibility, but I believe expansions in such directions will increase responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Unreason and neogods</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/unreason_and_neogods/</link>
       <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/unreason_and_neogods/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;I respect but ultimately reject the rationalists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; Are you unaware of the rationalists? I better explain then, the rationalists are a group of ai researchers who spread &lt;em&gt;propaganda thru harry potter fanfiction&lt;/em&gt;; and effectively at that, if you&amp;rsquo;ve heard of ai safety &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt; it likely had their hand at play, you can find them at lesswrong and the founding text is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hpmor.com/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;harry potter and the methods of rationality&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; by Eliezer Yudkowsky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;. What&amp;rsquo;s with that look. &lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m entirely serious&lt;/em&gt;&amp;hellip;. It&amp;rsquo;s not mad, if anything they are very effective and I&amp;rsquo;d take notes. Anyway enough about them, I wish to discuss a subculture within them, which I&amp;rsquo;ve heard described as &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;unreason&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;, not quite a founder but the writings of &lt;a href=&#34;https://slatestarcodex.com/&#34;&gt;Scott Alexander&lt;/a&gt; are probably a good place to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned two authors, maybe it would best to compare them thru their books(was this a literary device all along?). And wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you know it &lt;a href=&#34;http://unsongbook.com/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Unsong&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is a lovely book to compare to &amp;ldquo;hpmor&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In unsong, the story opens with the early space missions&amp;hellip;. hitting the sky, showing that the other stars and the sun and moon were nothing but lights in the sky and the earth was special. This broke the physical universe revealing a world underneath where &amp;ldquo;bible codes&amp;rdquo; exist and do work. Then you follow anarchists fix the world within the context of this apparently geocentric religious world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In hpmor, it&amp;rsquo;s the story of a &amp;ldquo;raised by scientists&amp;rdquo;, harry potter takes science to the magic world and&amp;hellip; well saves the magic world with science, and shit on backwards logic of said magic world every step of the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, hpmor is still a worthwhile read but it has no respect for nonscientific points of view in the sightless. &lt;em&gt;Reading intelligent characters with a rich inner world that walk thru their thought process is a treat&lt;/em&gt;, which is there. But &lt;em&gt;unsong takes the lowest rungs of the apparent intellectual social hierarchy, flat-earthers, schizos, etc., and &lt;strong&gt;treats their world view as a real thing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (which then begs the question if this is what you believe why doesn&amp;rsquo;t this or that sort of thing happen?) Furthermore, it&amp;rsquo;s not as fairytale and mary-sue like, the group of heroes, being intelligent is an asset among many. In hpmor, harry is a student, with zero knowledge of magic with plot amour and &lt;strong&gt;THE SCIENCE&lt;/strong&gt; and he does so much in a single fucking year with this &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HAMMER&lt;/strong&gt; and world of nails.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So to compare and contrast the two ideas: Rationalists would generally believe science is reaching for perfection, unreason&amp;hellip;ists would see it as a new intuition of knowledge, even an important one worthy of consideration but one &lt;em&gt;of many.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this &lt;a href=&#34;https://plato.stanford.edu/entries/pragmatism/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;American pragmatism&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Epistemological_anarchism&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Epistemological anarchism&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, some other idea I&amp;rsquo;m unaware of a title for?, an idea without a title and yet articulated?, I don&amp;rsquo;t know and I digress. So unreasonists are considering religion when frankly the rationalists are not. Let&amp;rsquo;s get to the next bit of that title, neo gods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If religion is worth looking into even as a lesser intuition than science; &lt;strong&gt;why?&lt;/strong&gt; Are there perhaps possible institutions of knowledge that could take something from religion and improve science? Why what a dangerous mind you have reader, asking that sort of question, are you perhaps willing to talk to flat earthers? Careful of the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;taint&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; of the conspiracy theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scott did make a suggestion of an idea in his essay on &lt;a href=&#34;https://slatestarcodex.com/2014/07/30/meditations-on-moloch/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;molock&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, which I will be calling a neo-god. What I will suggest is making a pantheon of neo-gods. Let me define it really quick:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meta-physical without challenging physicalism; these gods are/should be (((real))), believing in them should produce better predictions about the world. But &lt;del&gt;god damn&lt;/del&gt; &lt;em&gt;science sex it&lt;/em&gt;, people that &lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; believe in physicalism are &lt;em&gt;terrifying&lt;/em&gt;. The world is made up of particles bouncing around, it&amp;rsquo;s unethical to genocide a city to let god take who he will to a supposed heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They should have personalities. The human mind tells stories, stories with characters. This is the point, to think about abstract things the way the human mind works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They should be amoral or capable of being morally criticized. Perfect gods that define morality was so last century, mine are evil(not a requirement)&amp;hellip; and we may want to plot to kill them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the original essay useful, Scotts neo-god moloch is fairly influential for a reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If one is useful, &lt;em&gt;why not more&lt;/em&gt;, why not allow me to seed your pantheon with my own:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;moloch&#34;&gt;Moloch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To summarize the original essay, (and to set a style); Molock is the god that promises you a victory to win a battle if you ritually kill a child. His hand is there when cancer kills a host, when there is a nuclear arms race that prevents futher space exploration, in dollar actions, and prisoner dilemmas in a defecting state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is filled with glee when two armies sacrifice a child each, as that joy of that death with more than zero-sum of conflict is alone would make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ra&#34;&gt;Ra&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(This I got from lesswrong but don&amp;rsquo;t know where)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ra is a sungod&amp;hellip; a cruel &lt;em&gt;unmerciful&lt;/em&gt; one. He is the god of unchecked moralism, puritans, drug prohibitions, communists&amp;hellip;. &lt;strong&gt;scientism&lt;/strong&gt;, and rationalists. Sinners are to be punished to prevent sin as that will build heaven. But alas heaven never comes and the sinners weren&amp;rsquo;t prevented. All your left with are burnt witches, poisoned moonshine, and Mr. Hyde.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ra cares little of sinners suffering &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;they deserved it&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t care about the timeline for perfection, it will come when it&amp;rsquo;s done. Perfection is of infinite value when built. So all prices are worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Privacy, tolerating evil, loving humanity for its own sake; else the sun will &lt;em&gt;melt your wings&lt;/em&gt; and you&amp;rsquo;ll fucking &lt;em&gt;land on me&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;god-of-the-copybook-headingshttpswwwpoemhuntercompoemthe-gods-of-the-copybook-headings&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.poemhunter.com/poem/the-gods-of-the-copybook-headings/&#34;&gt;God of the copybook headings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The god of &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;old&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; people saying &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;old&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; things, on one hand, old wisdom, on the other hand ending slavery was once a novel idea. This is the god understood by Jordan Peterson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The least evil of the gods I suggest, but the poem&amp;rsquo;s author literally wrote &amp;ldquo;white man&amp;rsquo;s burden&amp;rdquo;. Negotiate with him carefully with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/G._K._Chesterton#Chesterton&#39;s_fence&#34;&gt;Chesterton fences&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it in old English and it rhymes, &lt;em&gt;it must be true&lt;/em&gt;; unless of course it isn&amp;rsquo;t. If you never change how can you know?, but if it never changes what&amp;rsquo;s keeping it that way?, &lt;em&gt;and how will it hurt you?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An old man telling you to eat your vegetables inbetween his racial slurs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;evolution-the-blind-idiot-god&#34;&gt;Evolution (the blind idiot god)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So poorly understood, people seem to think the idiot has a brain, but in reality, he was known by the name &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/3kQuMVffbWA&#34;&gt;azathoth&lt;/a&gt; to Lovecraft, god of noise and chaos. Not strength, or fitness. He makes all things only to genocide them all but a few, The Child damaging his toys, and we are those toys, tiny, small, and helpless&amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;already mutilated.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darwin hoped a kind god was behind it all; the followers of darwin misheard and thought this god was kind and went ahead and shared his &amp;ldquo;kindness&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-state&#34;&gt;The state.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who watches the watchman? The evil god of my political beliefs. But perhaps that&amp;rsquo;s a different essay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;closing-thoughts&#34;&gt;Closing thoughts.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m dropping this as is, don&amp;rsquo;t make me an owner of the idea. Expand on it without a care to coherency. Scott was doxxed and I don&amp;rsquo;t know of any writers to take his place, in lesswrong or in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are ideas in &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/WRKHYefEKcA&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;jreg&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://polcompball-anarchy.fandom.com/wiki/Epistemological_Anarchism&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;polcompball&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; but with politics; I believe it should be more abstract however, and some emphasis on reading books, I hear dem mak ppl smrt.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>alchemy games</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/alchemy_games/</link>
       <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/alchemy_games/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m making a crafting game, and I have opinions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The standard triple A crafting system is just a many-currency system, nothing that necessarily provides value. Not that I&amp;rsquo;ve played many such games, but just hearing that criticism when I&amp;rsquo;m not excited by say the terraria&amp;rsquo;s system which has you fighting specific bosses multiple times to get specific currency with 18 will get you shoes 19 will get you pants and 25 will get you a gun. If it&amp;rsquo;s even further dumbed down I can&amp;rsquo;t see value in it at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So do I hate crafting&amp;hellip; well no, I quite enjoyed Cultist Simulator, which as a core machinic has a 5 slot &amp;ldquo;ritual&amp;rdquo; that can take the majority of the cards in the game, when the late game definitely had over a hundred cards. While not all combinations work, that&amp;rsquo;s still quite the combinatorial problem if you brute-forced it. But here&amp;rsquo;s the thing, I didn&amp;rsquo;t, I eventually figured out the gamey systems under it which sapped its magic, but there were rhyme and reason to it and loads of flavor text with hints. Like &amp;ldquo;combine corpses with winter&amp;rdquo; is a hint everywhere and it makes a liability, having a corpse when your hiding from the fbi, into an asset, a zombie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hints and flavor text, and esoteric logic. 10/10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are too afraid to be esoteric in general, it&amp;rsquo;s rare to hear a coherent response to theism, instead, you get Richard Dawkins. Not Lovecraft in the silver key:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He had turned to the gentle churchly faith endeared to him by the naive trust of his fathers, for thence stretched mystic avenues which seemed to promise escape from life. Only on closer view did he mark the starved fancy and beauty, the stale and prosy triteness, and the owlish gravity and grotesque claims of solid truth which reigned boresomely and overwhelmingly among most of its professors; or feel to the full the awkwardness with which it sought to keep alive as literal fact the outgrown fears and guesses of a primal race confronting the unknown. It wearied Carter to see how solemnly people tried to make earthly reality out of old myths which every step of their boasted science confuted, and this misplaced seriousness killed the attachment he might have kept for the ancient creeds had they been content to offer the sonorous rites and emotional outlets in their true guise of ethereal fantasy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hardly a secret that I lean into such thought, altho I doubt you had the words in mind. So how to lead the dull into a rich world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, the plan is to double down on the hints and flavor text, putting far more effort into it than the actual gameplay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So coining a new genre, what is the element of an alchemy game:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A crafting system that is properly largely combinatorial to not have brute force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A live updating knowledge base to help guide the player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recipes can&amp;rsquo;t be formulaic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Reclaim mod keys</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/reclaim_mod_keys/</link>
       <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/reclaim_mod_keys/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;So you learned bash, and you set up a hotkey deamon of some sort and your ready to edit your dotfiles like a good /g/ fren to have a &amp;ldquo;productive&amp;rdquo; system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, all your programs use all the easy to remember hotkeys. You only have ctrl and alt and 36 keys. Are you suppose to ctrl+alt+shift+o+m to open your music player?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever is a newfren to do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/pepehands.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find one with broken fingers&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its simple we kill capslock and reclaim super.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install &amp;ldquo;xmodmap&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;xcape&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make the following file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;.Xmodmap&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;clear lock
keycode 66 &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; Hyper&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;\_&lt;/span&gt;R
add Mod3 &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; Hyper&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;\_&lt;/span&gt;R
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;add these lines to your autostart script (such as bspwmrc)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;xmodmap ~/.Xmodmap
xcape -e &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;Super\_L=Super\_L|Shift\_L|space&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;and rewrite your run menu keybinding to be super+shift+space (sxhkdrc)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;super + shift + space 
	rofi -show &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; ~/.config/wallpaper.sh_
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;And you have 2 new mod keys, super and hyper. And you to can be a cool haker with 20 workspaces and a tiling wm. Btw sxhkd calls hyper &amp;ldquo;mod3&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>What I want from metaprogramming</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/what_i_want_from_metaprogramming/</link>
       <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/what_i_want_from_metaprogramming/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Let me just list some quick opinions on meta programing to lay some groundwork, these could be separate rants on their own:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inheritance is annoying to maintain, ducktyping is great and 90% of the time will just be correct and comfy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fuzzy human standards are better than formal standards, I and everyone else expect addition to be associative, even if most people don&amp;rsquo;t know what associative means. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how to check associativity automatically that won&amp;rsquo;t have false negatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Templates can do most things I want, even if how c++ does templates is an ugly verbose lisp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have to check if it&amp;rsquo;s working correctly as an user anyway, so why try to verify its correct in strange abstract meta-programming land?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that in mind I expect the following things from metaprogramming:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. A way to define a generic function that takes any type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. A way to define op overloads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. A way to overload a type&amp;rsquo;s functions if I wish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d. A way to copy a type with modifications. &lt;code&gt;Nullable(T)&lt;/code&gt;
should be easy to write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;e. A community editable rough standard for what op overloads mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;f. A way to mix in and out strings/compilable data that can be modified compile time by standard code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, D does (a) and (b) verbosely but correctly. It attempts (c) and (d) but fails in sutle ways(alias this, but that&amp;rsquo;s a rant). (E) happened once(it&amp;rsquo;s what a range is) but doesn&amp;rsquo;t have an actual community-level process. My genetic opRadix does this, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a wiki to go edit to state my assumptions or look if someone defined something similar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in my ideal world, I would have capital letters be automatic generic templates, &lt;code&gt;T&lt;/code&gt; would be disallowed for a type name and just mean straight up, this function is generic. &lt;code&gt;T foo(T a)&lt;/code&gt;. Drop the lispyness entirely, make the sane thing simple and inlined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would then have lua-like op overloads super-global master table, denoted by the preface of &amp;ldquo;op&amp;rdquo;, &lt;code&gt;string opstring(int a)&lt;/code&gt;, would define the way ints are converted to strings globally. To avoid conflict, allow setting a priority, no bullshit on scoping or complex contracts, or whatever nonsense people are suggesting, just an int compare and make the std defaults negative numbers and user templates default to zero, throw an error if two are equal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An op overload table for &lt;code&gt;T&lt;/code&gt;, and what that implies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly string mixins, and mixouts(being an inverse), I still don&amp;rsquo;t see the value in Jai AST trees whatever. I have learned how to parse strings from countless places, I have the tools, and it&amp;rsquo;s presumably part of a good std. If it&amp;rsquo;s a new data type, what&amp;rsquo;s preventing repeating the c++ templates being an ugly lisp mistake?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>tiling DE part 3 The problem</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/tiling_de_part_3_the_problem/</link>
       <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/tiling_de_part_3_the_problem/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;So if tiling is so great why isn&amp;rsquo;t everyone using it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/considerthefollowing.png&#34; alt=&#34;considerthefollowing.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone is in the habit of being wrong. Just generally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historical inertia. Most software that has been written to be in the standard floating environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Composing workflows means composing applications. Which are spotty in the general user space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, look at this timer app given an unusual size:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/tomate-normal.png&#34; alt=&#34;tomate-normal&#34; style=&#34;max-width: max-content&#34;&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/tomate-borked.png&#34; alt=&#34;tomate-borked&#34; style=&#34;max-width: max-content&#34;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trash, unusable trash, awful, horrifying, jank. Its only collection of buttons and some numbers &lt;strong&gt;make it work&lt;/strong&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s a touch tricky but getting it to work properly but isn&amp;rsquo;t rocket surgery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every app that doesn&amp;rsquo;t resize properly is something I have to consider when I set up a workspace. A constrant that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/crazymonkyyy/pomodomo&#34;&gt;my&lt;/a&gt; timer app for example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/pomodomo-normal.png&#34; alt=&#34;pomodomo-normal&#34; style=&#34;max-width: max-content&#34;&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/pomodomo-borked.png&#34; alt=&#34;pomodomo-borked&#34; style=&#34;max-width: max-content&#34;&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/pomodomo-extra.png&#34; alt=&#34;pomodomo-extra&#34; style=&#34;max-width: max-content&#34;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look it, varous sizes and all work; &lt;em&gt;rocket surgery&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why? Why does mine work, when presumably the other one had more help from a toolkit and probably a less lazy dev; the &amp;ldquo;toolkits&amp;rdquo; are for floating wm&amp;rsquo;s, all of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the unaware, programmers don&amp;rsquo;t remake everything from scratch, in this case, if your making a GUI app, you use a toolkit, a collection of software to make buttons and text and system theming work. They are usually tied to an OS or a desktop environment in the case of gtk and qt. In my opinion, its the benefit of a DE is having a toolkit define how to handle fonts and colors. Both the programmer and the user want a system color theme, I as a user don&amp;rsquo;t want half my apps to be blinding theme, and prefer dark themes.

&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/notepad.png&#34; alt=&#34;notepad&#34; style=&#34;max-width: max-content&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/myeyes.gif&#34; alt=&#34;myeyes&#34; style=&#34;max-width: max-content&#34;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I, as a programmer, don&amp;rsquo;t give a rats ass about color theory, let someone else solve the problem of picking colors. And really really do not want to deal with the madness that is font rendering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So apps made with toolkits tend to fit nicely with their associated wm/os. But tiling wm&amp;rsquo;s don&amp;rsquo;t have one, at all. So the first order of business for making tiling better would be to make one, that places more emphasis on resizing. Which is actionable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>I want a tiling de part 2 your workflow</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/i_want_a_tiling_de_part_2_your_workflow/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/i_want_a_tiling_de_part_2_your_workflow/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the thing, you use janky tiling as is. It&amp;rsquo;s frankly rare to find someone engaging with their window manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I expect you to do a very small subset of actions with your computer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You full screen a web browser, always, no exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You use a software suite that requires fullscreen and if it&amp;rsquo;s a complex task it&amp;rsquo;s built-in and has its own rolled tiling system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You use the light tiling systems that most desktops have been adopted, by dragging the software to the side of the screen. Windows calls it &amp;ldquo;snap assist&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these while the window can in theory be defined by the user, in reality, you did a ritual you have the system do some math in the background to handle windowing for you; and really trivial things as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ide&amp;rsquo;s are generally speaking two text editors split horizontally with a terminal. I have text editors and a terminal installed, and I like my actual terminal better than the usually subpar one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/vscode-screenshot.gif&#34; alt=&#34;vscode-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is hardly uncommon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/bitwig.png&#34; alt=&#34;bitwig&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/blender.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;blender&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/cutemarked.png&#34; alt=&#34;cutemarked&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/gummi.png&#34; alt=&#34;gummi&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/Kdenlive.png&#34; alt=&#34;Kdenlive&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/toonz.png&#34; alt=&#34;toonz&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking, you have a toolbar, split the window into half or thirds, if you hide something it&amp;rsquo;s with tabs. You&amp;rsquo;d need some sort of sane tabbing interface, but tabbing is something a window manager can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet every program must reimplement the logic, and you can&amp;rsquo;t replace the terrible bits, &lt;em&gt;you can&amp;rsquo;t compose your workflow&lt;/em&gt;. Its the half baked general idea that someone else thought poeple would like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your ide is awful like the something from JetBrains, which takes seconds to start up and likely crashes. My ide is a 10 line bash script, and I picked my text editor and terminal separately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/bspwm.png&#34; alt=&#34;bspwm&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;cd $1
textadept -f &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;ls&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &amp;amp;
bspc node -p east --follow
textadept -f -n &amp;amp;
bspc node -p south -o .6 --follow
nemo $1 &amp;amp;
sleep &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
bspc node -p south -o .15 --follow
alacritty --working-directory $1 &amp;amp;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUITE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; confindent in this, you don&amp;rsquo;t half hide windows like they are papers on a desk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>use my code</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/use_my_code/</link>
       <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/use_my_code/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve written some public code during my time with D but no one is using it, use my code(listed is rough order of quality)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;range-matchhttpsgithubcomcrazymonkyyyrange-match&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/crazymonkyyy/range-match&#34;&gt;Range-match&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Range match, is a partial implementation of pattern matching. Focused on cleanly allowing complex &amp;ldquo;stuctured&amp;rdquo; programming. The main detail is that its requires the logic to be written using ranges such as 1&amp;lt;=x&amp;lt;=3. Replacing particularly nasty if-else chains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;genertic-radixhttpsgithubcomcrazymonkyyyradix&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/crazymonkyyy/radix&#34;&gt;Genertic radix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A specialized fast sort, countary to poplur belief radix sort can be used for more then unsigned ints. It will require a bit of work and a bit of thoery, but as the basic unit of computation contains more infomation then the bool of the comparision sorts it should be faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;layouthttpsgithubcomcrazymonkyyylayoutexperiment&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/crazymonkyyy/layoutexperiment&#34;&gt;Layout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A experiment to impliment css grids stand alone. See my rants on tiling window managers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;monkeydatahttpsgithubcomcrazymonkyyymonkeydata&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/crazymonkyyy/monkeydata&#34;&gt;Monkeydata&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &amp;ldquo;aosoa&amp;rdquo; template to try and make this data-oriented design primitive comfy to work with and not a bunch of manual work like it would be in c or the clusterfuck of boilerplate that is unity ecs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trash-utility-fileshttpsgithubcomcrazymonkyyydatastuctureplaygroundtreemastercopy20and20pasted20ulility20files20of20questionable20quality&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/crazymonkyyy/datastuctureplayground/tree/master/copy%20and%20pasted%20ulility%20files%20of%20questionable%20quality&#34;&gt;trash utility files&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>I want a tiling DE part 1</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/i_want_a_tiling_de_part_1/</link>
       <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/i_want_a_tiling_de_part_1/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;I want a tiling desktop environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; let me explain:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you normal computer user, everything you&amp;rsquo;ve known was based on the &amp;ldquo;desktop metaphor&amp;rdquo;, your an office worker in the black and white days, and your work gets a doohicky that confuses you. You don&amp;rsquo;t have time to learn anything, you need to work on the documents and fax them to management. So they made a half baked translation of your old work into what computers are doing. It&amp;rsquo;s fucking awful, but its what they tried, so you would store your work in a filing cabinet, you would take labeled folders out of the filing cabinet to take to your desk and you would take files out of the folder to then edit; on your desktop. And for some godforsaken reason, because those papers would be moved manually, it was deemed more user friendly to make the &amp;ldquo;paper&amp;rdquo;/windows floating as if they were paper on a desk like fucking cavemen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was intended to be invisible and everyone got used to it, but it&amp;rsquo;s wrong. In the modern era, after people used these computers for decades, you instantly full-screen everything or drag them to the side to spilt the screen in half. Because computers can and should manage windows for you. That splitting the window in half is weak tiling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the function of a window manager is to manage places for programs to draw their pictures, to then display them. A floating window manager is like a mother of 8 managing the pictures of children on the fridge using magnets, you drag around the taskbar/magnet to move the paper. A tiling window manager is like a well organized scrapbook, with pages/workspaces, you don&amp;rsquo;t cover up a photo, you make new pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what&amp;rsquo;s the difference between a window manager and a desktop environment?, mostly scale; for example kde has a little thing to connect a phone to your computer in a fancy pants sharing clipboards, files and even emulating a mouse from the touch screen. Bspwm doesn&amp;rsquo;t have an android app to emulate a mouse, bspwm is made up of a total of three binaries, I don&amp;rsquo;t even know how to count how many kde has, but let&amp;rsquo;s just say 1000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kde is an extreme example, what I would want would be more like lxde/qt project, maintaining a few dozen or so small &amp;ldquo;natural&amp;rdquo; projects, your notepads, your music players, all tied together so they look the same and have the same dependencies and have a bit of lube t make them fit together better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it stands tiling wm have a special requirement in that the wm have resize demands, not suggestions. For a well organized automated system, you must fit where you&amp;rsquo;re placed, several simple apps simply don&amp;rsquo;t or act weirdly. From the web the term is &amp;ldquo;reactive&amp;rdquo;, finding apps that are adequately reactive is hard. Its simply not on any other projects checkbox that a window at 100x200 pixels should have some functionality, even if that app is a music player and that could easily fit a play and pause button.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>brown folded eggs</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/brown_folded_eggs/</link>
       <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/brown_folded_eggs/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Sooo.. I like soft eggs, but traditionally the soft egg styles are reserved for fancy shit, french omelets, quite frankly I will not be beating eggs for 5 minutes for half a meal, listening for butter &amp;ldquo;singing&amp;rdquo;, or damaging a pan for a daily breakfest. Or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZCh1gnN_j-g&#34;&gt;tornado/dressed rice&lt;/a&gt;, also fantastic, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think I can twist my fingers to do that shit daily, and I don&amp;rsquo;t always have leftover rice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A soft egg is a simple concept, high heat and move the finished eggs out of the way, yet the fear about undercooked eggs has pushed it to the edges; and I say NO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a medium frying pan heat 3(yes 3 don&amp;rsquo;t be a snob) pats of butter on medium- medium high heat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beat 5 eggs with soysause, salt, pepper and cayenne, quite heavily. Break up 90% of the egg white strings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the butter is past &amp;ldquo;singing&amp;rdquo;, litterally boiling and taking on some color, add the eggs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a pair of chopsticks, pull the film/sheet of cooked eggs into wrinkly piles repeatly, until no new egg fills the botton of the pan, tilt the pan to drain uncooked eggs onto the bottom of the pan and give it 30 more seconds to then dump on a plate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>how should standard libs be managed</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/how_should_standard_libs_be_managed/</link>
       <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/how_should_standard_libs_be_managed/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;So, an under appreciated feature of a lang is the std. Honestly at this point I think it could make or break a lang. Having a good std means its easy to write acceptable code from the gate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C-style langs historically require immense effort to &lt;strong&gt;render&lt;/strong&gt; hello world, I believe this is the singular reason webshit is winning, because the js can draw things &amp;ldquo;easily&amp;rdquo; with the js os known as chromium. While C has these whole nightmares to make a cross platform ui. Why tho?, couldn&amp;rsquo;t you just have simple window rendering in the std? You probaly wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want to write a game engine with an std but text drawing and simple shapes should be there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also there was this whole mess with python with its trasition from 2 to 3. I&amp;rsquo;m fuzzy on the details but it sounds like they over did it and assumed far to much complience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then D lang, whitch turn down my appication to try to improve the std, in &amp;ldquo;SAoC&amp;rdquo; and has horror storys on community managiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With those issues in mind, heres roughly what I would do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Std writing should be trivial to get into, you can sumbit an &amp;ldquo;expmerimental&amp;rdquo; lib sith almost no approval process. The writter of that lib owns thier experimental branch and can write to it as they see fit. No bullshit about not changing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Libs have major version numbers on the libs where &amp;ldquo;std.whatever&amp;rdquo; points to the current stable version, &amp;ldquo;std.whatever.expermental&amp;rdquo; points to the raw expermental version getting live updates, with a limit of non-bug fixing updates being 6 months apart. While there is depercation, old versions of the std lib should never become unaccessable. &amp;ldquo;Import std.functions.3&amp;rdquo; should load 3rd major version of the code even if &amp;ldquo;functions&amp;rdquo; is on its 7th version. So even if there is a breaking change, you just look up the version number and append it to single lines, or if your working on something meant to be hyper stable write a style guide that requires std imports to specify the version number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The std should be expansive, window rendering, several competing collections of data stuctures, the kicten sink. There should be standards of quality, but proving a general usecase should not be a thing that holds something back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When theres is conflict where both sides have working code, then some sort of bureaucratic process should get involved; for example an simd xml reader thats super complient with xml version $currentminusone and a oo xml reader that adapted quickly, if &lt;strong&gt;both&lt;/strong&gt; been written then there is a reason to have some conflict other who wrote better code and who has the std.xml namespace and you need a process to handle it(with the loser getting std.xmlnew or something). But before that point anyone anti having something in the std can fuck right off either they can choose not to use that code or get working on thier own code to prove it can be done better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tools should be easy to come by, and the unmoderated ecosystem with random biuld tool seems awful, and std thats a very large toolbox so you don&amp;rsquo;t need an outside system should be preferred.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>email me</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/email_me/</link>
       <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/email_me/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Has anyone found this site yet? If so, email me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:monkyyy@cocaine.ninja&#34;&gt;monkyyy@cocaine.ninja&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>web is bloat what would I do</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/web_is_bloat_what_would_i_do/</link>
       <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/web_is_bloat_what_would_i_do/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;The webshit is webshit, I imagine anyone who manages to find this blog will agree that the socail media web is bad or is a &amp;ldquo;systems&amp;rdquo; programmer who looks at webshit with disgust; so not going into detail, so what would I replace it with?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see 3 main tasks as part of the web:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Layout&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rich text with a focus on links&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generic system aided user messages&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I would add a 4th, a flash replacement, but that would be another rant.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Html only managed the 2nd, and the first historically was a nightmare, poeple had space partition trees in thier mind for so long; &lt;strong&gt;my&lt;/strong&gt; wm is &amp;ldquo;Binary Space Partition Window Manager&amp;rdquo; and let me tell you, poeple don&amp;rsquo;t think in 1.5d trees they think about layout in grids I like tiling wm&amp;rsquo;s but its still jank. And to my knowlegde no one has solved the thrid problem cleanly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;layout&#34;&gt;Layout&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, layout is futher sub divided into 2 parts, grid defination and grid coloring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you give poeple enough dials in your grid layout they can compose websites that most poeple find pleasing, whether thats think  margins, and collection of images, having a logo at the top corner and a wall of text, whatever. Trational html defined &amp;ldquo;frames&amp;rdquo; which are like the space trees; don&amp;rsquo;t, learn from that mistake. You grab a list of 95% of the definations of css grids poeple ussally poke and allow poeple to define it as the header of the web page. Oh and have muliple for different screen sizes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Followed by that header is a grid coloring; even if humans think in grids they do this silly thing where they will define content as being bigger then a single grid cell; so you have an n by m 2d array of lets say 8 length strings which will &amp;ldquo;color&amp;rdquo; the boxes. The strings link to a block of text below and boxes that share a &amp;ldquo;color&amp;rdquo; are touching are combined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rich-text&#34;&gt;Rich text&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown is pretty good. The links are a bit of a strange choice but you have blocks of text that is markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh and color hints; not color definations; thats a topic I&amp;rsquo;m not super on top of but color multiplication is possible, so the user would have thier system theme that has a list of colors, a dark theme would have white text on black and light theme would have black text on white, a web site could ask that thier background is more blue and broswer would make a dark blue for the dark theme and a light blue for the blinding theme via some sort of color muliplier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you have a header of the name of the content for the layout, some color hints, with a block of text of probaly an expanded markdown; like my blog is generated from markdown, its functional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets say when injecting an image or a video in markdown that the file type determines what subsystem renders it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;system-aided-user-messages&#34;&gt;System aided user messages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is the tricky bit, defining the 2 way communication; this would also go into the grid coloring system. And some heading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fundmentally what a pizza site is doing with its layers and layers of js is asking you for an order and some bank info; this is a message. And users are not going to be learning its internal data system and would be very upset if they moved things around during a refactor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d point at zenity (it creates popup windows for bash scripts, like files manager, calenders etc.), and some posix. You have some posix syntax to generate a file with some user help and a system of envermental varibles like say $VISAID, and it will generate and send a text file according to some spefication when the user hits send.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Makepiza&amp;rdquo; of the pizza website could append $temporderdetails while &amp;ldquo;checkout&amp;rdquo; could be something like, encypt(pizzasitekey,$temporderdetails $VISAID userinput &amp;ndash;tip &amp;ldquo;20.00 usd&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>I want to go to an antimask protest</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/i_want_to_go_to_an_antimask_protest/</link>
       <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/i_want_to_go_to_an_antimask_protest/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Naturally, I&amp;rsquo;m a &amp;ldquo;covid-denier&amp;rdquo;; despite the fact I made a death toll prediction feb 5th before the medical estimement raised the alram, I did my speculating, made my conclusion, and stated it to an hyper critical audence saying I was anti-science for thinking it would be worse then sars. Dispite enaging with the most important bit of science I believe in, motivated prediction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ceasefire.net/post/a239z5/300000_poeple_will_die_this_year_from_corona_virus&#34;&gt;Yes really. I predicted 300,000 deaths on feb 5th I will not be letting any one in any agrument on the topic off without explaining why they didn&amp;rsquo;t have a reasonable attempt. Having the world disagree with you but being right is always suffocating.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;. I fucking hate it all. Do none of you see the frenzy your in, the mental agony your in for a illness that doesn&amp;rsquo;t harm the young. Your very hard to love humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may as well restate my case again, any lockdown past the risk of medical shortages are a meme. The R0 is very very high, there is a point where everyone will be infected by an illness given a high enough R0. Any increase won&amp;rsquo;t infect more poeple and by simple logic a decrease to that point won&amp;rsquo;t save any lives either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They did nothing when it mattered then over corrected and did everything when it didn&amp;rsquo;t. Like an expecting mother who was on meth for the first 2 weeks of pregency, then converted to a cult that ate nothing but raw food. Exopental growth may take a bit but the outcome was set in motion. It will feel very unfair to that mother but I would rate the brith defect risk using numbers from methhead births.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of which we are close to 9 months since I&amp;rsquo;ve heard; its getting rather old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve asked 4chan, I tried reddit, I&amp;rsquo;ve googled, I&amp;rsquo;ve dug into new stories of past protests. 4chan and cnn are on the same page of &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;PANIC&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; and calling me crazy. And of course the majority of places feel censored. I want a local protest, I&amp;rsquo;ll probaly be awkward, as they will antivaxxers probaly but&amp;hellip;.. I don&amp;rsquo;t know maybe it will be satisfying in some way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>please stop the roits antifa</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/please_stop_the_roits_antifa/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/please_stop_the_roits_antifa/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;When this started, there was a video of a man being killed by police officers that generally speaking everyone agreed was murder. Today, that fact is disputed, there was a 17 year old who was either kkk member or an americain hero depending on who you ask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You went staight past, vague but consentous to improve the problem of police violence, to two competing thoeries of expanding police power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first is clear, trump is running on law and order. The arm of the repubicain party known as fox new has been showing images of voilence consistently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is far less obvious is that biden/harris is a dog wistle for law and order. If we presume that independent voters do an entire minute of research, a big ask but bare with me; they should find that either joe &amp;ldquo;crime bill&amp;rdquo; biden in fact added 80 something crimes to the death penelty list and expanded police power, and that harris is considered an over zealous proscutor. Biden alone is a blank slate that pushes in whatever the dnc decides should be the next president; or the maybe anti-bernie but doubling down on the feature of law and order democrates speaks that it was intended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuing the violence isn&amp;rsquo;t helping the case that the state is unnecessary or evil. For whatever reason this murder entered the public consensus, a rare event; and you wasted it, rotted it and left it out to smell. Fuck you ancoms this moment was valuable; learn from this mistake.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>D is rather good at commandline bodging</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/d_is_rather_good_at_commandline_bodging/</link>
       <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/d_is_rather_good_at_commandline_bodging/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;I have not seen this written down anywhere, and the pieces are seperated in the documation; But I assume it took effort to make pieces of this to work apperently correctly and comfy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;taking-command-line-input&#34;&gt;Taking command line input:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-d&#34; data-lang=&#34;d&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;main&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;string&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;[]&lt;/span&gt; s&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;){&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Besides element 0 being the command for posix reasons; its rather staight forward, your input is whatever you named s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;running-commands&#34;&gt;running commands:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-d&#34; data-lang=&#34;d&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; std.process&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;string&lt;/span&gt; userinput&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;executeShell&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;zenity --entry&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zenity pops up a window for the user to input something into, so these two lines of code will do the rather complicated thing of getting a string from the user, assuming its installed and not vomiting gtk warnings.
Read the fucking manual for bash tools and all that jazz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reading-files-lazily&#34;&gt;Reading files lazily:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bit more complicated, but you can read and write to files without any sort of hassle with the following pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in data.d&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-d&#34; data-lang=&#34;d&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;mystruct&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; i&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; f&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;bool&lt;/span&gt; b&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in foo.d&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-d&#34; data-lang=&#34;d&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; data&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; std.file&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;main&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(){&lt;/span&gt;
  mystruct a&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;mystruct&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;42&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1337.0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;//import std.process; executeShell(&amp;#34;touch store&amp;#34;);
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  write&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;store&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;,[&lt;/span&gt;a&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;]);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in bar.d&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-d&#34; data-lang=&#34;d&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; data&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; std.file&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;main&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(){&lt;/span&gt;
  mystruct a&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;exists&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;store&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;)){&lt;/span&gt;
    a&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;cast&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;  mystruct&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;[]&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;read&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;store&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;))[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;];&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;assert&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;a&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;42&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;assert&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;a&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;f&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1337.0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;assert&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;a&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; std.stdio&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;success&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;writeln&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I mean you could read in files as intended but do you really want to do that?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>bash scripting 1</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/bash_scripting_1/</link>
       <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/bash_scripting_1/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;So, in order to make writing a blog with images comfy I need a tool of some sort way to inject the infomation into the blog and set it up so it will be auto hosted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A software maximalist would set up a drag and drop interface, you would take your screen shot run over to m$ paint, paste your screen shot, then go to you document folder and hope you find it quickly then you drag and drop into your webshit website editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will not be doing that.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Instead I will write a bash script; to start with I need to gather up the pieces to bodge together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From my last blog post the markdown syntax in hugo was&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-md&#34; data-lang=&#34;md&#34;&gt;![&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;bleh&lt;/span&gt;](&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;bleh.png&lt;/span&gt;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;From past knowledge I know scrot has a &amp;ldquo;click a window to screen shot it&amp;rdquo; option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zenity to pop up a text box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for a good image cropping resize tool. &amp;ldquo;pix&amp;rdquo; seems good enough, as it a) opens the image when give it from the command line and b) automaticly is happy with overwriting the file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And something that will boop something into my copy and paste. Looking into xclip I find this syntax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;echo &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;hello&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; | xclip -selection clipboard

ctrl-v hello
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well thats jank but whatever &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve grabed my tools.&lt;/strong&gt; Time to unix them together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start with I&amp;rsquo;m going to go to my src/bash folder and touch and chmod a new file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;monkyyy@no bash&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;$ touch hugoimagesyntax

&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;monkyyy@no bash&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;$ chmod +x hugoimagesyntax
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Double checking the syntax, and that scrot tends to make png&amp;rsquo;s I write&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;echo !&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;$1&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;](&lt;/span&gt;$1.png&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;which unfornately clashes with bash, five tries later I got (and a post edit to make it link correct)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;echo &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;![&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;$1&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;](/images/&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;$1&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;.png)&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; | xclip -selection clipboard
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moving on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;monkyyy@no bash&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;$ touch blogscreenshot

&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;monkyyy@no bash&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;$ chmod+x blogscreenshot

bash: chmod+x: command not found

&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;monkyyy@no bash&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;$ chmod +x blogscreenshot
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;My hugo image folder is well&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ll copy and paste that
&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/nemo_images_propertys.png&#34; alt=&#34;nemo_images_propertys&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which I will need to format to make a cd command. Next man-paging scrot:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;man scrot

SYNOPSIS
       scrot &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;options&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;file&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
       
       -s, --select
              Interactively &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;select&lt;/span&gt; a window or rectangle with the mouse.  See -l and  -f
              options.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I try a few things but get this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;cd ~/src/hugo/content/images
scrot -s $1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;which seems to be working correctly. So I add:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;pix $1.png
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;it unfornately errors out, probaly a racing error. Adding a sleep&amp;hellip;.. and it also doesnt work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait no, scrot doesnt automaticly add .png ops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And lets end off with calling my earlier file, bring my script to this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;cd ~/src/hugo/content/images
scrot -s $1.png
pix $1.png
~/src/bash/hugoimagesyntax $1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;to finish things off I drop down to home to try to make a final command to put into my general system keybroad shortcut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading thru zenitys man page&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;--entry
              Display text entry dialog
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;then, wrapping it in $() to make it run correctly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;monkyyy@no ~&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;$ ./src/bash/blogscreenshot &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;zenity --entry&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;it seems to be working so I copy and paste it into my keybindings config, skhdx, or whatever it is; you should have something simuliar, if you don&amp;rsquo;t get one; running arbitary commands on a key press is very useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;super + Print
  ./src/bash/blogscreenshot &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;zenity --entry&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;And like magic since I live in this opinionated miniumalist world, I can do something quite complex with quite a bit of automation, at any point by pushing super+printscreen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/I_am_king.png&#34; alt=&#34;I_am_king&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will of course need to edit this to format it nicely and to get my numerous spelling mistakes but this is why I stay minimal. This probaly wasn&amp;rsquo;t the bestm but hopefully you can get the raw bodging attitude that you should take.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>up and running</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/up_and_running/</link>
       <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/up_and_running/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;I believe I&amp;rsquo;ve fixed all the webshit issues. And this should just work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a little unsure of the process to get images so here is me attemping to upload one&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://monkyyy.science/images/softwaresucks1.png&#34; alt=&#34;softwaresucks&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey it works I can work with that, a little big but sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets see if I can publish it in under 2 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Lysander Spooner is still relevant</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/lysander_spooner_is_still_relivant/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/lysander_spooner_is_still_relivant/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;The world is still shit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The naive look at history and think it is over, the holocaust can&amp;rsquo;t happen again, democracy is peak humanity, slavery ended and enjoying djanjo unchained and or the white giult football movie makes you a good person, good enough that you can go harass poeple on twitter in fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The naive may be slightly stiring in thier sleep this year, but make no mistake, &lt;em&gt;the majority will never wake, and the majority of those who wake will be groggy.&lt;/em&gt; Lets review some basic facts of the world:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a genocide ongoing in china, if you believed anything nice about yourself when you heard about the holocaust or slavery, consider your &amp;ldquo;I would&amp;rsquo;ve helped the underground railroad&amp;rdquo; implies right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prisions are filled with poeple who never had a trail and airn&amp;rsquo;t even accused of a (real) crime&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you work in a standard way 30% of your income will go to fund war in the middle east&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poeple get awfully caught up in using xim/xer pronouns and not using the word blacklist, recycling(which means it gets burned in china, please don&amp;rsquo;t recycle) or if ethics should be this or that. &lt;strong&gt;FUCK THAT. Consider the following:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your a gun manufacturer and a uyghur activist askes for a shipment of gun off book, consider ignoring the fbi database and doing that. Prehaphs you&amp;rsquo;ll be part of a &lt;a href=&#34;http://praxeology.net/LS-PAS.htm&#34;&gt;plan for the abolition of slavery.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If someone is on drugs and being a nuance, maybe don&amp;rsquo;t call the cops after all &lt;a href=&#34;https://cdn.mises.org/vices_are_not_crimes.pdf&#34;&gt;vices are not crimes.&lt;/a&gt;  In fact consider not calling the cops unless you specifically want that person dead as cops do have ichy trigger fingers in $current_year, and yes even if they are white.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dodge some taxes, it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freedomforallseasons.org/TaxFreedomEmail/LysanderSpoonerNoTreason.pdf&#34;&gt;no treason&lt;/a&gt;. You personally never signed the founding documents of your nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spooner is the father of anarcho-capitalism; the movement is young and its been poorly stewarded, and honestly even after all my reading, this is all half-baked. &lt;strong&gt;BUT&lt;/strong&gt;, there airn&amp;rsquo;t many extermist groups willing to biuld something and very few who oppose causal voilence and the world is always in need of drastic change. Its a short list for even viable political ideologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe what the world needs is poeple who don&amp;rsquo;t do evil, dragging their way out of the shit of the past by sluggish movements towards what may in fact be sunlight. What system we should biuld are rather up in the air, but consider that if democracy is peak humanity, humanity will likely nuke itself after maybe 50 more years of this soul crushing joke of a society; with the one gasp of air from industerialization we may need to get out of the shitpile now least we never get another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t really believe in postive obligation, asking someone to hide a jew means they were a target, they were under duress, but mind your negitive obligations calling the cops on someone for drug use is very much a choice. Accepting money for censorious chineses corps stopping poeple from talking about hong kong, is a choice. Joining a twitter mob, is a choice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>copy and paste imports in d</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/copy_and_paste_imports_in_d/</link>
       <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/copy_and_paste_imports_in_d/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Orginally when I was looking for a lang, I had a single red flag when looking at d&amp;rsquo;s web site; which when compared to other randomly selected webshit langs is amazing. However it still stands that the d devs shit on good parts of c, when allow me to be blunt &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;c is the best lang aviable;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; thats more of a reflection on the other langs that exist, its really showing its age, but I stand by that statement until a suitable c replacement gets made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-md&#34; data-lang=&#34;md&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;&amp;gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:italic&#34;&gt;We are better the c
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:italic&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;&amp;gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:italic&#34;&gt;c is to much fun we cant have that
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:italic&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;&amp;gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:italic&#34;&gt;Using monkey as a negitive adjective to mean silly
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:italic&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;&amp;gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:italic&#34;&gt;Scoping is a good thing
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dlang.org/articles/mixin.html&#34;&gt;https://dlang.org/articles/mixin.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excuse me? That is not enough reverence to jank, c, or monkeys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I digress, I &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; c imports for being purely copy and paste, moving code around should the right of the programmer without restrictions, and scoping rules are &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;oft&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; a restriction, and can cause a rewrite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However they are possible in d, probally not intentionally so don&amp;rsquo;t show this to the devs, they may get some anti-fun ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-d&#34; data-lang=&#34;d&#34;&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;mixin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;import&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;foo.mix&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;));&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A bit of jank and shrill poeple who ever see your code being yelly are a small price to pay to avoid erroneous and non-comfy reformating or even leaving code where it doesn&amp;rsquo;t belong just to keep it in scope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will however need to use to -J=. compiler option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throw these options in your dub.json if your using dub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34; data-lang=&#34;css&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;dflags&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;:[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;-mixin=mix&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;-J=./source&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;extraDependencyFiles&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;:[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;\*.mix&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt; 

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;And I&amp;rsquo;m declaring the (monkyyy) offical standard style guide for using copy and paste imports in d require them to have a .mix file extension; its on page 4.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>indroduction</title>
       <link>https://monkyyy.science/posts/indroduction/</link>
       <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://monkyyy.science/posts/indroduction/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello internet, I&amp;rsquo;m monkyyy, I&amp;rsquo;m an opinionated asshole. Welcome to my storage of opinions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually I may get an email for this site, or a comment section. But currently I&amp;rsquo;m just screaming into the void trying to be comfy while doing it. The world is censory out there, and all based on website that runs slow, drops infomation and don&amp;rsquo;t nesserily allow me to inline an image or cross out text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will probaly focus on my following opinions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;anarcho-capitalism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;anti-scientism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;software minimalism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;programing games in d&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider yourself warned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
 </channel>
</rss>
